我想创建一个目录。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: I wanna
create a table of contents.
所以我想看看文档里还有什么。
So I want to be able to see
what else is in the docs.
要做到这一点，作为今天的捷径,
And to do that,
as kind of a shortcut today,
我们只需要创建一个组件就可以了。
we will just create a component
that does that for us.
所以这个方法的工作原理是，我们要进入我们的组件。
So the way that that works is,
we're going to get into our components.
让我们创建一个叫做 table-of-contents. js 的东西。
And let's just create something
called table-of-contents.js.
在这里面，我们将从一些风格开始
And inside of that we'll just
start out with some style so
我们不需要分阶段进行。
that we don't have to do that in phases.
因此，我们将 pragma 设置为 jsx，我们将从 theme-ui 导入 jsx。
So we'll set the pragma to jsx,
we'll import jsx from theme-ui.
然后我们还要导入 graphql，Link so
And then we're also going
to import graphql, Link so
我们可以把这些页面连接起来。
that we can link between the pages.
然后是盖茨比给我们的一个钩子，叫做 useStaticQuery。
And then a hook that Gatsby
gives us called useStaticQuery.
现在因为这不是一个模板，我们没有访问权限
Now because this is not a template,
we don't have access
到页面查询或上下文或变量或任何东西。
to the page queries or context or
variables or anything.
所以我们要使用 useStaticQuery，这样我们就可以得到数据了。
So we're gonna use this useStaticQuery so
that we can get data out.
但需要注意的是，只有在不需要变量的情况下，才可以这样做。
But it's important to note that you can
only do this if you don't need variables.
您必须在 useStaticQuery 中对所有内容进行硬编码。
You have to hard code
everything in a useStaticQuery.
这就是为什么它是静态的。
That's why it's static.
你得不到动态的内容。
You don't get dynamic content.
首先，让我们设置组件本身,
So first,
let's set up our component itself,
桌面目录，如果我能拼出来的话。
TableOfContents, if I could spell it.
这里没有任何参数，我们将它作为默认值导出。
That doesn’t get any arguments and
we will export that as our default.
作为第一步，我们将在内部加载数据。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Inside we will,
as a first step, load our data.
那么让我们得到数据，这将是 useStaticQuery 的结果。
So let’s get the data and that’s gonna
be the result of useStaticQuery.
我们使用 graphql 标记来表示它确实是一个查询。
And we use the graphql tag to
signify that it is indeed a query.
我想要获得 allDocsPage 节点
And I wanna get allDocsPage nodes and
我需要这个 id，这样我们就可以用它作为反应钥匙。
I want the id, so
that we can use it as a react key.
我想要的标题，这样我们就可以有一些显示文本。
I want the title, so
that we can have some display text.
我需要路径，这样我们就知道，如果有人点击了链接，该把他们送到哪里。
And I want the path, so that we know where
to send somebody if they click the link.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 一旦我们得到了那些数据，它就会出现
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Once we’ve got
that data, it’s gonna come in and
存储在这个数据道具里。
be stored in this data prop.
实际上，盖茨比会在建造时间做这件事。
Gatsby will do this at build time,
actually.
所以我们不需要等待。
So we don’t need to await it or anything.
就组件而言，当它在浏览器上运行时,
It just as far as the component is
concerned when it runs on the browser,
那些数据早就存在了。
that data will already exist.
然后，为了方便起见，我们可以重命名页面
Then we can, for convenience,
let's rename pages and
我们去拿 data.alldock.nodes。
we'll get data.allDocsPage.nodes.
然后我们可以归还一件东西。
And then we can return a thing.
所以我们要返回的是，我们给它一个 div 以防万一
So the thing that we wanna return is,
we'll give it a div in case we
想要风格或添加一些边框或周围的东西。
want to style it or add some borders or
something around it.
我们暂时不会这么做，但是我们想让那扇门开着。
We're not gonna do that for now, but
we want to leave that door open.
让我们为它添加一个标题。
Let's add a heading to it.
所以我们会说探索文档。
So we'll say Explore the Docs.
然后我们会在一个列表中展示这些。
And then we'll just show these in a list.
那么让我们来看看我们的页面。
So let's map over our pages.
对于每个人，我们都要找出他们的身份，路径和头衔。
And for each one we're gonna get
out that id, path and title.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们可以返回一里。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And
we can return an li.
我们把钥匙设置成 id。
We'll set the key to the id.
在这里面，我们要使用一个链接。
And then inside of that,
we're gonna use a link.
我想把它链接到路径上，我想给它一些样式。
And I want that to link to the path and
I wanna give it some styles.
所以我想要的风格实际上是一个它是活跃的。
So the styles that I want are actually
gonna be one it's active.
这意味着当我们回顾当前页面时,
So what that means is,
when we're reviewing the current page,
我想展示一个稍微不同的风格，这样我们就知道我们在哪一页。
I wanna show a slightly different style so
we know what page we're on.
所以我们马上就要开始了。
So we'll do that in just a second.
然后我们想把它和标题联系起来。
And then we want that
to link to the title.
这就是将要展示的内容。
So this is what will be displayed.
当这是一个活动类的时候,
And then whenever this
is the active class,
盖茨比有这么一个好帮手。
Gatsby has this really handy helper.
这样我们就可以设置当前链接是什么时候
That will let us just set whenever
the current link is the one that's being
访问。
visited.
它只是为我们设置了一个类名。
It'll just set a class name for us.
所以我要把它设置为激活状态。
So I'm gonna set that to active.
所以现在我们进入了一些主题 UI 的东西，有点不同。
So now we're getting into some theme
UI stuff that's a little different.
我们想要有条件的样式。
We're wanting conditional styles.
我们希望这个组件只有在使用类时才有样式,
We want this component to only have
a style when we're using a class on it,
当它有一个活跃的类。
when it has that active class.
所以要做到这一点，我们可以使用一个非常标准的 CSS 和 JS 技术。
So to do that, we can use a pretty
standard CSS and JS technique.
它是使用与引用当前元素的符号。
Which is to use the ampersand which
references the current element.
然后我们用活动类修改它，在这里添加这个. active。
And then we modify it with the active
class by adding this .active here.
在这里面，我们可以应用任何我们想要的样式。
Inside of that we can apply
whatever styles we want.
假设我们希望我们的字体样式是斜体的。
So let's say we want our
font style to be italic.
我们会说我们希望文本装饰为无，因为它是当前的链接。
We'll say that we want the text decoration
to be none because it's the current link.
我们想淡化它作为一个链接，但不是实际上停用它作为一个链接。
We want to de-emphasize it as a link but
not actually deactivate it as a link.
然后我想更进一步
And then I want to go one step further and
实际上，我想告诉人们，这就是他们正在浏览的页面。
I actually want to tell people that
this is the page they're viewing.
所以我要使用 after 伪类。
So I'm gonna use the after pseudo class.
同样，我们只是把它作为一个字符串添加，然后在这里添加一个子对象。
And again we just add it as a string and
then add a subobject here.
我要设置内容。
And I'm gonna set the content.
这是值得注意的 CSS 和 CSS 中的内容
And this is worth noting
the content in CSS and
结果看起来像是双引号。
JS ends up looking like
it's double quoted.
因为你必须引用它一次才能使它成为 JavaScript 的属性。
Because you have to quote it once to
make it a property for JavaScript.
然后你必须为 CSS 引用它。
And then you have to quote it for CSS.
这意味着 JavaScript 和 JavaScript 都有单引号
Which means that we've got
single quotes for JavaScript and
然后我们有双引号的 CSS。
then we've got double quotes for CSS.
所以我把这个设置为。
So, I'm gonna set this as
the currently viewing.
这些是用于 JavaScript 的，这些是用于 CSS 的。
And so, these ones are for
JavaScript, these ones are for CSS.
这下我明白了，这下我完全明白了。
That's a gotcha, that definitely got me.
所以这就有点像试图把它钉在你的头上。
So it's worth just kind of like
trying to pin that in your head for.
当你将来尝试使用它的时候。
When you are trying to
use this in the future.
既然我们已经有了这个，我们应该可以直接使用它。
So now that we've got this,
we should be able to just use it.
让我们来看看我们的文档页面。
So let's go into our docs page.
我要把它扔进去。
And I'm just gonna toss it in.
让我们看看会怎么样。
Let's see how it goes.
因此，让我们从目录导入 TableOfContents。
So let's import TableOfContents
from table-of-contents.
我们可以把它放在底部。
And we can drop that right at the bottom.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 首先要启动网站,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Gotta
start the site first,
纱线工作区主题-开发。
yarn workspace theme-dev develop.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 重新装载，就这样，我们现在正在观看。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Reload, and
there we go, we're currently viewing.
因此，让我们添加一个额外的页面，以确保它按照我们预期的方式工作。
So let's add an extra page to make sure
that it's working the way we expect.
所以我们要去主题开发，在文档下，我要创建一个新的文件和
So we're going to theme-dev, under docs,
and I'm gonna create a new file and
我们叫它另一个 mdx。
we'll call it another.mdx.
所以我们会给它一个标题，让我们称之为另一个页面，我们会说更多的文档！
So we'll give it a title, let's call it
another page, and we'll say More docs!
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我们开始吧。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And there we go.
现在我们可以点击我们的页面了。
So now we can click around to our pages.
看看我们还有其他的页面。
And see that we've got
other pages in there.
他们正以我们所期望的方式出现。
They are showing up the way we expect.
主题是热重载，我们创建了这个文件。
The theme is hot reloading,
we created that file.
我们不必停下来重新启动它。
We didn't have to stop and restart it.
就这么捡起来了。
Just picked it right up.
我们的目录正在做我们想做的事情。
And our table of contents is
doing what we wanted to do.
因此，有一个很好的地方来保存我们的工作。
So there is a good place to save our work.
所以让我们把所有的加起来。
So let's git add all.
看看我们都做了些什么，好吗？
Take a look at what we've done, okay?
所以我们更新了文档页面，使用了我们的目录。
So we updated the docs page
to use our table of contents.
写了那个目录组件。
Wrote that table of contents component.
创建了一个新的文档页面。
And created a new docs page.
所以我们要承认这一点。
So we'll commit that.
说添加目录，把它推上去。
Say add table of contents, push that up.